Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ wolfgangsinocruz (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Process Control
Process Automation
Automation

Languages

Tagalog

Certifications

TUV Functional Safety Engineer, Hardware/Software Development EIT, Engineer-In-Training Toastmasters - VP of Education Six Sigma Black Belt

TUV Functional Safety Engineer, Safety Instrumented Systems

Wolfgang Sinocruz, MS, MBA, PM

Project Management

Bellflower, California, United States

Summary

Solid experience in various facets of product/business development. Strong client management and technical expertise built from 20+ years of comprehensive management and engineering experiences. Versatile and results-driven in effectively propelling high profile, revenue generating projects to the marketplace. Experienced in managing complex hardware, software, and testing projects from prototype to production. Ardent problem solver and analytical thinking skills with a focus toward sustainable engineering solutions. Champion of innovation in leading transformational changes that enhances the organization's ability to adapt to evolving industrial trends and strong market presence. A dedicated professional committed to the implementation of best-in-class business practices and processes.

- Project Performance Management and Quality
- Risk Management
- Scrum Master and Project Stages
- Financial & Resource Management
- Electrical & Computer Engineering
- Global Team Management
- Hardware & Software Development Lifecycle
- Contracts and Procurement
- Strategic Project Planning, Execution and Control
- Safety & Reliability Engineering
- Stakeholder / Customer Management
- Business Operations Optimization

Experience

Panasonic Avionics Corporation Project Manager December 2022 - Present (1 year)

Cloudvirga

Director, Technical Program Management January 2021 - October 2022 (1 year 10 months)

Irvine, California, United States

- •Effectively managed the execution of project activities with a high rate of ontime delivery on significant revenue-generating projects for a growing SAAS fintech startup.
- •Developed strong client relationships based on trust, timely interactions, transparency, personalization, problem solving, and meeting/exceeding business objectives.
- •Took the lead in optimizing the Client Implementation of technical configurations and processes in the Staging and Production SaaS platforms.
- •Oversaw successful Requirements validation and User Acceptance testing, leading to Pilot, Production, and Go-Live events. Clients include large mortgage lenders across US.
- •Lead working sessions with clients to go over product demos, as well as troubleshoot technical issues throughout the various phases of the projects.
- •Worked effectively and professionally with internal and external partners, including clients, vendors, and other agency partners.
- •Managed internal scrums within engineering to successfully resolve critical features and bugs and develop plans for software build deployments to the different clients.

Panasonic Avionics Corporation Engineering Project/Program Manager June 2013 - June 2020 (7 years 1 month)

Lake Forest, CA

- •Managed effective execution of overall project activities with a high rate of ontime delivery on significant revenue-generating projects.
- •Oversaw efficient transition across the full comprehensive product development lifecycle from requirements, design, prototype, system integration, testing, and production release.
- •Lead successful deployments of GCS and IFE systems certifications and Entry-Into-Service installations in various types of Airbus and Boeing aircraft configurations.
- •Achieved a high rate of customer success and satisfaction with major airline customers, including Qantas, United, WestJet, and Air New Zealand.
- •Managed the complex integration on the full suite of hardware and software products, including air and groundside systems, inflight services, iOS and

Android applications, payment system, offload diagnostics, WISP, GCS services, and others.

- •Reduced quality-related issues through effective change control practices, test coverage, regression and iteration-based approach.
- •Managed quick turn-around on resolutions to internal and field issues, through root cause analyses and rapid deployment of product updates.
- •Effectively led high priority short flow projects through effective collaboration with various stakeholders and vendors at a global business environment.
- •Drove cost-saving, by up to 50% in some cases, by utilizing resources and corporate assets to more value-add efforts, and increased work efficiency with parallel activities that takes advantage of competencies, load balancing, and resource sharing.
- •Contributed to the innovative transformation of the organization as an advocate for continuous improvements by identifying lessons learned and vocalizing ideas based on modern product development and project management techniques.
- •Maintained a strong dynamic project team through effective collaboration, agility, cohesion, and transparency in communication.

Invensys Operations Management Senior Product Development Project Manager June 2007 - April 2013 (5 years 11 months) Lake Forest, CA

Managed the overall project planning, performance and execution, including scope, budget, schedule, quality, and resources to ensure that projects achieve the business objectives.

- Worked closely with cross-functional teams (Engineering, Product Assurance, Marketing, Supply Chain, Manufacturing, Customer Service, Quality, Project Management, and Portfolio) to obtain buy-in and support of the final product.
- Managed projects throughout the different stages of product lifecycle from prototype, to Pilot and Production to ensure that products were introduced to the market on-time. Earned multiple awards recognizing on-time project completion.
- Monitored and controlled various metrics of the project, including schedule and cost variances, indices, and forecasts to optimize performance relative to the project baselines and performed corrective actions where applicable.
- Lead a successful global project team (Germany, England, Mexico, India, Canada, France) by implementing effective channels of communication and

various team building strategies. Coordinated timely engagements among the global team.

- Proactively managed defects and risks to maximize product quality, reliability, and performance. Drove rate of issue disposition to be comparable to the rate of defect discovery.
- Built lasting business relationships with customers, contractors, suppliers, and vendors to maintain a reliable network that is aligned to address project needs.
- Worked closely with various agencies (TUV, ATEX, CSA, FM, NRC, WurldTech) to obtain timely issuance of product certifications and minimize non-compliance.
- Helped ensure adherence to the industry standards (IEC, IEEE, MIL, ISO) and compliance to internal procedures. Typically held successful audits with zero non-conformance findings.
- Implemented techniques/methods such as Six Sigma, CMMI, Agile, and Critical Chain in accordance to organizational initiatives. Reduced task estimates by 25% or more.

Invensys Operations Management Senior Hardware Engineer November 2004 - April 2007 (2 years 6 months) Irvine, CA

Designed and tested safety critical control systems. Evaluated system reliability and availability.

- Designed and analyzed safety-instrumented systems through the use of robust engineering design methodologies and in accordance to various standards (IEC 61508, 61511, 61131, EPRI).
- Performed Failure Mode, Effect, and Criticality Analysis (FMEA) to systematically ensure fault coverage through diagnostics and other fault detection schemes.
- Analyzed reliability variables and models such as failure rates, MTBF, PFD, MTTF, SFF, SIL, Diagnostic Coverage, and Markov models to quantify fault tolerance.

Los Angeles Department of Water and Power Electrical Engineer April 2004 - October 2004 (7 months) Los Angeles, CA Designed security, access control, and surveillance systems. Collaborated with different construction teams to ensure coordinated effort and optimal use of resources and equipment.

SoHaR

Electrical Engineer October 2003 - January 2004 (4 months) Culver City, CA

Evaluated military and commercial hardware systems to assess safety, reliability, risks, and performance. Performed circuit analysis to reveal the

fault characteristics of the system during the different stages of the mission.

UC Irvine

Instructor

September 2001 - December 2002 (1 year 4 months)

Irvine, CA

Taught C/C++, Analog and Digital Systems university level courses.

SoHaR

Electrical Engineer
June 2000 - September 2001 (1 year 4 months)
Beverly Hills, CA

Evaluated military and commercial hardware systems to assess safety, reliability, risks, and performance. Performed circuit analysis to reveal the fault characteristics of the system during the different stages of the mission.

Education

UC Irvine

Master's degree, Electrical and Computer Engineer (2011 - 2012)

UC Irvine

Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering (1994 - 1999)

UC Irvine

Certificate, Project Management · (2007 - 2009)

University of La Verne

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Leadership and Management · (2005 - 2007)

University of Phoenix

Doctoral of Business Administration, Business and

Management · (2011 - 2014)